Guide to the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives Subject Files ALBA.VF.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Film: "Shouts from the Wall: Voices of the Spanish Civil War" (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Film: "Sierra de Teruel" (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Film: "Silencio Roto" (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Film: "Spain in Exile" (1946) (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Film: "Spain in Flames" (Box Shared Tamiment 062, Folder 21)
- Film: Spanish Civil War (U.K. Newsreels) (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Film: "Spanish Earth" (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Film: "To Die in Spain" (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Film: "A Valley in Spain" (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Film: "Vieja Memoria" (Jaime Camino) (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Film: "With the Abraham Lincoln Brigade in Spain" (Cartier-Bresson) (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Films: Spanish Civil War, General, and Abraham Lincoln Brigade, undated (Box 4, Folder 15, Box Shared Tamiment 189, Folder 16)
- Finnish and Finnish-American Volunteers (I) (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Finnish and Finnish-American Volunteers (II) (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Folkways (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Fondation Internationale d'Etudes Historiques et Sociales (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Franco and Franco Regime (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Franco and Franco Regime (Oversize) (Box Shared Tamiment 126, Folder 9)
- Franco, Volunteers for (Box 10, Folder 2)
- French Volunteers (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Friends and Family of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Friends and Family of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (Oversize) (Box Shared Tamiment 126, Folder 10)
- Friends of the American Lincoln Brigade, Boston Branch (Box Shared Tamiment 126, Folder 11)
- Friends of Spain (London, England) (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Friends of the Lincoln Battalion: Morningside Branch (1937) (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Friends of the Spanish Republic (Box 10, Folder 7)
- German Democratic Republic (Box 10, Folder 8)
- German Volunteers (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Glasgow Volunteers (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Graves: International Brigades (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Greater Boston Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Greek Volunteers (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Greek-American Volunteers (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Grupo Sacco y Vanzetti (International Brigade Unit) (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Grupo Tierra Y Libertad (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Guernica (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Guernica Anniversary: Italy (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Guernica: Exhibited at Valentine Gallery, NYC, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Guernica: Peace Museum (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Guerrilla Warfare (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Harvard University: Widener Library (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Harvard/Radcliffe Student Unions (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Hashomer Hatzair, NY: Articles (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Hebrew Orphan Asylum (Sam Katz) (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Himno de Riego and Other Songs, undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
- Hispanic Volunteers (J. Fernandez Article) (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Hoover Institution: Bolloten Collection (Guide) (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Hospitals (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Hospitals: Benissa (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Hospitals: Cambrils (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Illinois Volunteers (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Indian Volunteers (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Industrial Workers of the World (Box 11, Folder 17)
- International Brigades: 59th Battalion (Box 11, Folder 18)
- International Brigade Memorial Trust (UK) (Box 11, Folder 19)
- International Brigades: Battalion List (Box 11, Folder 20)
- International Brigades: General (Box 9, Folder 1)
- International Brigades: Moscow Archive, Photograph Collection Guide (Box 11, Folder 21)
- International Institut voor Sociale Gescheidenis (Amsterdam): CNT Photo Archive (Box 12, Folder 1)
- International Labor Defense of Spain (Box 12, Folder 2)
- International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union: Support for Spanish Republic (Box 12, Folder 3)
- International Youth Commission (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Irish and Irish-American Volunteers (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Italian Intervention (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Italian Volunteers (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Italian-American Volunteers (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Israel Association of Volunteers of the International Brigades in Spain (1936-39) (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Jaily News (Box 12, Folder 10, Box Shared Tamiment 044, Folder 4)
- Jarama (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Jarama: Memorial at Moratea de Tajua (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Jewish Currents: Articles (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Jewish Daily Forward: Articles (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Jewish Labor and the Spanish Civil War, by Michael L. O'Flaherty (Box 12, Folder 15)
- Jewish Life: Articles (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Jews in the Spanish Civil War (I) (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Jews in the Spanish Civil War (II) (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Jews in the Spanish Civil War: Bagon Paper (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Jews in the Spanish Civil War: Bibliographies (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Jews in the Spanish Civil War: Bund (Poland), G. Pickhan (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Jews in the Spanish Civil War: Butwin, J. (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Jews in the Spanish Civil War: Diamant, David (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Jews in the Spanish Civil War: Lustiger Paper on German and Austrian Jews (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Jews in the Spanish Civil War: Medem, Gina (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Jews in the Spanish Civil War: Prago, Albert (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Jews in the Spanish Civil War: Rockman, Alan S., M.A. Thesis (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Jews in the Spanish Civil War: Rothenberg, Joshua, Article on Botwin Company (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Jews in the Spanish Civil War: Sichon, G. E. (Dr. Gabriel Ersler) (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Jews in the Spanish Civil War: Sugarman Project (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Jews in the Spanish Civil War: Women (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Jews in the Spanish Civil War: Zaagsma, Gerben (articles and thesis) (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Josef Stalin Battalion (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Journalism (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Journalists (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Juventudes Socialistas de Espana (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Kampfer und Freunde der Spanischen Republik 1936-1939 e.V. (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Kansas Volunteers (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Komitee der Antifaschistischen Widerstandskampfer (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Kriegel, Frantisek, Dr., article by G. E. Sichon (Dr. Gabriel Ersler) (Box Shared Tamiment 126, Folder 12)
- Labour Party (UK) (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Labour Party Archives, Manchester: Inventory (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Latin American Volunteers (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Left Book Club (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Life Magazine: Spanish Civil War Coverage (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Ligue de Mutiles et Invalides de la Guerre d' Espagne: Temoignage (Box 5, Folder 27)
- List of Dead, Wounded, and Missing (Mar-Apr 1938) (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Lithuanian Volunteers (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Lovestoneites and POUM (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Luxembourg: Les Amis des Brigades Internationales (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Macedonian Volunteers (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Mackenzie Papineau Battalion, Americans in (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Mackenzie Papineau Battalion Veterans (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Madrid: Atrocities (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Madrid, Battle of (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Mail Service for International Brigade Volunteers in Spain (Box 5, Folder 37)
- Marine Cooks' and Stewards' Association (Box 5, Folder 38)
- Maritime Workers: Volunteers in Spain (Box 5, Folder 39)
- Masters Mates and Pilots of America (Box 5, Folder 40)
- May Day 1938: "Viva el Ejercito Popular" (Box 5, Folder 41)
- Medal Issued by Spain for International Brigades (Box 5, Folder 42)
- Medical Aspects of the Spanish Civil War; Bibliography compiled by Victor Berch (Box 5, Folder 43)
- Medical Bureau to Aid Spanish Democracy (later Medical Bureau...mittee to Aid Spanish Democracy) (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Medical Bureau to Aid Spanish Democracy (later Medical Bureau...id Spanish Democracy) (Oversize) (Box Shared Tamiment 126, Folder 13)
- Medical Bureau to Aid Spanish Democracy (later Medical Bureau...panish Democracy), Boston Branch (Box 5, Folder 44)
- Medical Services and Personnel (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Medical Services and Personnel: Lavoz de la Sanidad de la XV Division (photocopies) (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Medical Services of the International Brigades in Spain, P. Kolarov (Box 5, Folder 45)
- Memorials (Box 5, Folder 46)
- Mexican Volunteers (Box 5, Folder 47)
- Mexico (Box 5, Folder 48)
- Michigan Volunteers (Box 5, Folder 49)
- Minnesota Volunteers (Box 5, Folder 50)
- Montana Volunteers (Box 5, Folder 51)
- Monuments (Box 5, Folder 52)
- Monuments: Madison, Wisconsin (Box 5, Folder 53)
- Monuments: New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 54)
- Monuments: San Francisco (Box 5, Folder 55)
- Monuments / Sculpture: Shifrin, "David and Goliath" (Barcelona) (Box 5, Folder 56)
- Morocco and Moroccans (Box 5, Folder 57)
- Musicians' Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy (Box 5, Folder 58)
- National Caucus of Labor Committees: New Solidarity Article on Spanish Civil War (Box 5, Folder 59)
- National Council for Evacuated Children (Box 5, Folder 60)
- National History Day: ALBA Project (Box 5, Folder 61)
- Native American Volunteers [missing as of 8/2010] (Box 5, Folder 62)
- Naval History (Spanish Civil War) (Box 5, Folder 63)
- New England Volunteers (Box 5, Folder 64)
- New Jersey Volunteers (Box 5, Folder 65)
- New Leader: Articles [missing as of 8/2010] (Box 5, Folder 66)
- New Mexico Volunteers (Box 5, Folder 67)
- New School: Spanish Civil War Course (Box 5, Folder 68)
- New York Joint Committee to Lift the Embargo (Box 5, Folder 69)
- New York Public Library (Box 5, Folder 70)
- New York State Volunteers (Box 9, Folder 9)
- New York University: King Juan Carlos of Spain Center (Box 5, Folder 71)
- New York University Spanish Civil War Course Syllabi (Box 5, Folder 72)
- New York University Volunteers (Box 5, Folder 73)
- New Zealand Volunteers (Box 5, Folder 74)
- Nicaragua (Box 5, Folder 75)
- North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy (Box 9, Folder 10)
- North Axholme School: "Volunteers for Spain" series (Box 5, Folder 76)
- Nurses (Box 5, Folder 77)
- Ohio Volunteers (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Ohio Volunteers (from J. Brandt Scrapbooks, ALBA 236) (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Olympics, Barcelona, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Palestine/Israel Volunteers (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Pamphlets: Rare [Photocopies], circa 1937-1938 (Box 9, Folder 22)
- Pamphlets: Southworth Collection (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Pamphlet: The Story of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 189, Folder 18)
- Partido Obrero de Unificacin Marxista (POUM) (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Partit Socialista Unificat de Catalunya (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Passport List (U.S. Senate Subcommittee Research, 1957) (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Paterna: Executions (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Peruvian Volunteers (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Photographers: Chim (paper by Carole Naggon) (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Photographs: ALBA Volunteers, Photocopies with Names ID'd (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Pittsburgh Volunteers (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Plaza de Oriente (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Poetry: Kenneth Rexroth (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Poetry: Spanish Civil War (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Polish Volunteers (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Portugal and the Franco Regime (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Portuguese Volunteers (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Postal History (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Posters (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Posters: Blythe Bennett Paper (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Prado Museum, Bombing Of (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Prison Camps (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Prisoners: General (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Prisoners: Italian Fascists (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Prisoners: Lists, from Archives in Salamanca and Avila (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Prisoners: Political (Franco Regime, 1960's-1970's) (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Prisoners: Summary of Laws and Locations of Prison Archives in Spain (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Pro Niños Españoles Brigadas Internationales, 1936 (Box Shared Tamiment 189, Folder 17)
- Progressive Labor: "Lessons of People's War in Spain 1936-1939" (1974) (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Puerto Rican Volunteers (Box 6, Folder 29)
- Puppet Theatre (Spain) (Box 6, Folder 30)
- Radio Project: "Corpus Duende" (Box 6, Folder 31)
- Radio Project: Peter Garvie (Box 6, Folder 32)
- Red Cross: Archives (Box 6, Folder 33)
- Refugees: France (Box 6, Folder 34)
- Renau Artwork (1938) (Box 6, Folder 35)
- Repatriation of Abraham Lincoln Brigade Volunteers (Box 6, Folder 36)
- Romanian Volunteers (Box 6, Folder 37)
- Roosevelt Administration and the Spanish Civil War (Box 6, Folder 38)
- Russian Participation: Fascist (Box 6, Folder 39)
- Rutgers University: "Rutgers Remembers the Spanish Civil War ...dia," Student Publication (1978) (Box 6, Folder 40)
- Sailing Lists (Box 6, Folder 41)
- Salamanca: Spanish Civil War Archives (Box 6, Folder 42)
- Santander (Box 6, Folder 43)
- Scottish Participation: Aid (Box 6, Folder 44)
- Scottish Volunteers (Box 6, Folder 45)
- Seattle Volunteers (Box 6, Folder 46)
- Seminar: "Americans in Spain, The International Brigade" (Northeast Illinois University, 1999) (Box 6, Folder 47)
- Ships: Ciudad de Barcelona, Sinking of (Box 6, Folder 48)
- Ships: Erica Reed (Box 6, Folder 49)
- Sim (Rey Vila) (Box 6, Folder 50)
- Smith Act Trials, List of Cases and Defendants (1948-1956) (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Smithsonian Institution (Box 6, Folder 51)
- Socialist Appeal (Box 6, Folder 52)
- Socialist Party (U.S.) (Box 6, Folder 53)
- Socors Roig de Catalunya, El (Box 6, Folder 54)
- Socorro Rojo Internacional (Box 6, Folder 55)
- Songs: Blythe Bennett Paper (Box 6, Folder 56)
- Songs: "'A Lyrical War': Songs of the Spanish Civil War," Laurence H. Birdsey (Box 6, Folder 57)
- Songs/Music (Box 6, Folder 58)
- Songs/Music (Oversize) (Box Shared Tamiment 126, Folder 14)
- South Dakota Volunteers (Box 6, Folder 59)
- Southern Illinois University (Box 6, Folder 60)
- Soviet Union: Participation (Box 6, Folder 61)
- Spain: Campaign against U.S.-Madrid Treaty (1976) (Box 6, Folder 62)
- Spain: Libraries and Archives (Box 6, Folder 63)
- Spain: Libraries and Archives (Albacete) (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Spain: Maps (Box 6, Folder 64)
- Spain: Ministerio de Defensa Nacional - Blank certificates (Box 6, Folder 65)
- Spain: Politics (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Spain Today: Special Bulletins (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Spain: Trips by Veterans and Friends (Box 6, Folder 66)
- Spanish Childrens Relief Fund (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Spanish Citizenship (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Spanish Civil War: Acronyms (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Spanish Civil War: Archives and Libraries (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Spanish Civil War Center, Proposal for (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Spanish Civil War: Dissertations on (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Spanish Civil War: General (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Spanish Civil War Historical Society (VALB) (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Spanish Civil War: Historiography and Bibliography (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Spanish Civil War Sites (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Spanish Civil War: "Turbulent Spain," National Geographic Magazine (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Spanish Democrats' Defense Fund (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Spanish Intellectual Aid (U.S.) (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Spanish Medical Aid Committee (U.K.): Bulletins (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Spanish Nationalism: Alvarez Junco paper (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Spanish Prisoners Revue (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Spanish Refugee Aid (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Spanish Refugee Appeal (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Spanish Refugee Appeal (Oversize) (Box Shared Tamiment 126, Folder 16)
- Spanish Refugee Relief Campaign (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Spanish Republican Government in Exile (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Subversive Activities Control Board (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Support for Spanish Republic (U.S.) (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Swedish Volunteers (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Swiss Volunteers (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Symposium: Literature of the Spanish Civil War: "Art and Ideology" (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Symposium: Spanish Civil War: The Aftermath (Cambridge, MA, 1986) (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Symposium: Tamiment Library (2007) (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Symposium: "Unfulfilled Dream" (Spanish Institute, 1981) (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Tampa, Florida: Spanish Civil War (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Tampa, Florida: Spanish Civil War (Oversize) (Box Shared Tamiment 126, Folder 15)
- Television: "Angels of the Last Pure War " (Mary Lou Reker) (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Television: "Between the Wars" (Eric Sevareid, 1978) (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Television: Spanish Civil War Series (Granada Television) (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Thaelmann Battalion (Box 7, Folder 33)
- Theatre: "The Artist Must Take Sides" (Box 7, Folder 34)
- Theatre: General (Box 7, Folder 35)
- Theatre: "No Pasaran" (Santa Monica) (Box 7, Folder 36)
- Theatre: "Red Bessie" (Box 7, Folder 37)
- Theatre: "To Barcelona" (Box 7, Folder 38)
- Theatre: Wolf, Roland," The Abraham Lincoln Brigade, A Play in Three Acts" (typescript) (Box 7, Folder 39)
- Theatrical Programs: Spain (Oversize) (Box Shared Tamiment 126, Folder 17)
- Tom Paine Brigade (Berkeley, CA) (Box 7, Folder 40)
- Trade Union Relief for Spain (Box 7, Folder 41)
- Transmissions Units (Transmisiones) (Box 7, Folder 42)
- Transport Workers (Box 7, Folder 43)
- Trotskyist Material (Box 7, Folder 44)
- United American Spanish Aid Committee (Box 7, Folder 45)
- United Spanish Societies to Aid Spain (Box 7, Folder 46)
- United States Committee for a Democratic Spain (Box 9, Folder 17)
- United States Foreign Policy and the Spanish Civil War (Box 7, Folder 47)
- United States State Department Confidential Central Files: Spain: Internal Affairs, 1930-1939 (Box 7, Folder 48)
- University of California (Box 7, Folder 49)
- University of California: San Diego (Box 7, Folder 50)
- University of Illinois: Spanish Civil War Collections (Box 7, Folder 51)
- Valencia (Box 7, Folder 52)
- Veterans' Benefits for Abraham Lincoln Brigade Veterans (U.S. Congress) (Box 7, Folder 53)
- Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Bulletin (Box 7, Folder 54)
- Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): Bay Area Post (Box 7, Folder 55)
- Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB) Collections: U...ornia Berkeley, Bancroft Library (Box 7, Folder 56)
- Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): Conference, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 57)
- Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): Dances and Balls (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): General (I) (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): General (II) (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): Historical Commission (Box 7, Folder 58)
- Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): New York Post (Box 7, Folder 59)
- Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): San Diego Post (Box 7, Folder 60)
- Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): Vietnam War (Oversize) (Box Shared Tamiment 126, Folder 18)
- Volkerbund (Geneva): Articles on the Spanish Civil War (Box 7, Folder 61)
- Volunteer for Liberty: History (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Volunteer for Liberty, Reprint Edition: Publicity Material (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Volunteer, The (Box 8, Folder 3)
- War Resisters League (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Washington D.C. Friends of Spanish Democracy (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Wayne State University Volunteers (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Welsh Volunteers (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Westcoast Volunteer (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Wisconsin Volunteers (Box 8, Folder 9)
- "Wise and Foolish Dreamers" Exhibit (Flat-file-folder 2 Right)
- Women in the Spanish Civil War (Box 8, Folder 10)
- World War II, Abraham Lincoln Brigade Veterans in (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Young Communist League: Challenge (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Young Defenders of Spanish Democracy (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Young People's Socialist League (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Yugoslav Medical Personnel (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Yugoslav Volunteers (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Yugoslav Volunteers: Udovicki Memoir (Box 8, Folder 17)